{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The number of simultaneous equations to be solved in the slope deflection method, is equal to :", "opta": "the degree of statical indeterminacy", "optb": "the degree of kinematic indeterminacy", "optc": "the number of joints in the structure", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Maximum size of a fillet weld for a plate of square edge is", "opta": "1.5 mm less than the thickness of the plate", "optb": "one half of the thickness of the plate", "optc": "thickness of the plate itself", "optd": "1.5 mm more than the thickness of the plate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The treatment that should be given to the water from a deep tube well is :", "opta": "pre-settling only", "optb": "coagulation and flocculation only", "optc": "filtration only", "optd": "disinfection only", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "On sag (or valley) curves the available sight distance is determined based on :", "opta": "design speed", "optb": "height of obstacle", "optc": "height of driver eye", "optd": "night-time driving conditions", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a steady radial flow into an intake, the velocity is found to vary as (1/r2), where r is the radial distance. The acceleration of the flow is proportional to", "opta": "1/r5", "optb": "1/r3", "optc": "1/r4", "optd": "1/r", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The wall shown in the below figure has failed. The cause of failure or the error made in the design of the failded wall is :", "opta": "deep slip surface failure", "optb": "overturning", "optc": "no proper drainage in the clay backfill", "optd": "translational failure", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The span to depth ratio limit is specified in IS : 456-1978 for the reinforced concrete beams, in order to ensure that the", "opta": "tensile crack width is below a limit", "optb": "shear failure is avoided", "optc": "stress in the tension reinforcement is less than the allowable value", "optd": "deflection of the beam is below a limiting value", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A two span beam with an internal hinge is shown below.  The conjugate beam corresponding to this beam is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Some of the structural strength of a clayey material that is lost by remoulding is slowly recovered with time. This property of soils to undergo an isothermal gel-to-soil-to-gel transformation upon agitation and subsequent rest is termed :", "opta": "Isotropy", "optb": "Anisotropy", "optc": "Thixotropy", "optd": "Allotropy", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The capacities of \"One-way 1.5 m wide sidewalk (persons per hour)\" and \"One-way 2-lane urban road (PCU per hour, with no frontage access, no standing vehicles and very little cross traffic)\" are respectively.", "opta": "1200 and 2400", "optb": "1800 and 2000", "optc": "1200 and 1500", "optd": "2000 and 1200", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Is 459-1978 recommends to provide certain minimum steel in a RCC beam", "opta": "to ensure compression failure", "optb": "to avoid rupture of steel in case a flexural failure occurs", "optc": "to hold the stirrup steel in position", "optd": "to provide enough ductility to the beam", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Shear stress develops on a fluid element, if :", "opta": "the fluid is at least", "optb": "the fluid-container is subject to uniform linear acceleration", "optc": "the fluid is inviscid", "optd": "the fluid is viscous and the flow is nonuniform", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A hydraulic turbine has a discharge of 5 m3/s, when operating under a head of 20 m with a speed of 500 rpm. If it is to operate under a head of 15 m, for the same discharge, the rotational speed in rpm will approximately be", "opta": "433", "optb": "403", "optc": "627", "optd": "388", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A nozzle discharging water under head H has an outlet area \"a\" and discharge coefficient cd = 1.0. A vertical plate is acted upon by the fluid force Fj when held across the free jet and by the fluid force Fn when held against the nozzle to stop the flow, the ratio Fj/Fn is", "opta": "1/2", "optb": "1", "optc": "2", "optd": "2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A hydraulic turbine develops a power of 104 metric horse power while running at a speed of 100 revolutions per minute, under a head of 40 m. Its specific speed is nearest to one of the following :", "opta": "100", "optb": "628", "optc": "523", "optd": "314", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Prandtl mixing length for turbulent flow through pipes is", "opta": "independent of shear stress", "optb": "a universal constant", "optc": "zero at the pipe wall", "optd": "independent of radial distance from pipe axis", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 40\u00b0 slope is excavated to a depth of 10 m in a deep layer of saturated clay of unit weight 20 kN.m3; the relevant shear strength parameters are cu = 70 kN/m2 and \u03c6u = 0. The rock ledge is at a great depth. The Taylor's stability coefficient for \u03c6u = 0 and 40\u00b0 slope angle is 0.18. The factor of safety of the slope is :", "opta": "2.0", "optb": "2.1", "optc": "2.2", "optd": "2.3", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lysimeter and Tensiometer are used to measure respectively, one of the following groups of quantities :", "opta": "Capillary potential and permeability", "optb": "Evapotranspiration and capillary potential", "optc": "Velocity in channels and vapour pressure", "optd": "Velocity in pipes and pressure head", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ruling minimum radius of horizontal curve of a national highway in plain terrain for ruling design speed of 100 km/hour with e = 0.07 and f = 0.15 is close to", "opta": "250 m", "optb": "360 m", "optc": "36 m", "optd": "300 m", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Principle involved in the relationship between submerged unit weight and saturated weight of a soil is based on", "opta": "Equilibrium of floating bodies", "optb": "Archimedes' principle", "optc": "Stokes' law", "optd": "Darcy's law", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The kinetic energy correction factor for a full developed laminar flow through a circular pipe is", "opta": "1.00", "optb": "1.33", "optc": "2.00", "optd": "1.50", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The slope of the e-log p curve for a soil mass gives :", "opta": "coefficient of permeability, k", "optb": "coefficient of consolidation Cv", "optc": "compression index, Cc", "optd": "coefficient of volume compressibility, mv", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The modulus of subgrade reaction is obtained from the plate bearing test in the form of load-deformation curve. The pressure corresponding to the following settlement value should be used for computing modulus of subgrade reaction", "opta": "0.375 cm", "optb": "0.175 cm", "optc": "0.125 cm", "optd": "0.250 cm", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "X-component of velocity in a 2-D incompressible flow is given by u = y2 + 4 xy. If Y-com-ponent of velocity 'v' equals zero at y = 0, the expression for 'v' is given by", "opta": "4y", "optb": "2y2", "optc": "-2y2", "optd": "2xy", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Consolidation in soils", "opta": "is a function of the effective stress", "optb": "does not depend on the present stress", "optc": "is a function of the pore water pressure", "optd": "is a function of the total stress", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A cantilever beam of length L and a cross section with shape factor f supports a concentrated load P as shown below  The length LP of the plastic zone, when the maximum bending moment equals the plastic moment MP, given by", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The minimum area of tension reinforcement in a beam shall be greater than", "opta": "0.85 bd/fy", "optb": "0.87 fy/bd", "optc": "0.04 bd", "optd": "0.4 bd/y", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an iceberg, 15% of the volume projects above the sea surface. If the specific weight of sea water is 10.5 kN/m3 , the specific weight of iceberg ir kN/m3 is", "opta": "12.52", "optb": "9.81", "optc": "8.93", "optd": "7.83", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A reinforced concrete column contains longitudinal steel equal to 1 percent of net cross-sectional area of the column. Assume modular ratio as 10. The loads carried (using the elastic theory) by the longitudinal steel and the net area of concrete, are Ps and Pc respectively. The ratio Ps/Pc expressed as percent is", "opta": "0.1", "optb": "1", "optc": "1.1", "optd": "10", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A steady discharge of 1 cumec flows uniformly in a rectangular channel 1 m wide at a depth of 250 mm. The slope of the channel bed is :", "opta": "adverse", "optb": "steep", "optc": "critical", "optd": "mild", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In reinforced concrete, pedestal is defined as compression member, whose effective length does not exceed its least dimension by", "opta": "12 times", "optb": "3 times", "optc": "16 times", "optd": "8 times", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Flexible pavements derive stability primarily from :", "opta": "aggregate interlock, particle friction and cohesion", "optb": "cohesion alone", "optc": "the binding power of bituminous materials", "optd": "the flexural strength of the surface course", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The permissible bending tensile stress in concrete for the vertical wall of an R.C. water tank made of M 25 concrete is :", "opta": "8.5 N/mm2", "optb": "6.0 N/mm3", "optc": "2.5 N/mm2", "optd": "1.8 N/mm2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cylinder strength of the concrete is less than the cube strength because of", "opta": "the difference in the shape of the cross section of the specimens", "optb": "the difference in the slendeness ratio of the specimens", "optc": "the friction between the concrete specimens and the steel plate of the testing machine", "optd": "the cubes are tested without capping but the cylinders are tested with capping", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A water treatment plant is required to process 28800 m3/d of raw water (density = 1000 kg/m3, kinematic viscosity = 10-6 m2/s). The rapid mixing tank imparts tank a velocity gradient of 900s-1 to blend 35 mg/l of alum with the flow for a detention time of 2 minutes. The power input (W) required for rapid mixing is", "opta": "32.4", "optb": "36", "optc": "324", "optd": "32400", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The depth of tension crack in a soft clay (\u03c6u = 0) is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A single rapid test to determine the pollu-tional status of river water is :", "opta": "biochemical oxygen demand", "optb": "chemical oxygen demand", "optc": "total organic solids", "optd": "dissolved oxygen", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The vertical stress at depth z, directly below the point load p is (k is a constant)", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vane tester is normally used for determining in situ shear strength of :", "opta": "soft clays", "optb": "sand", "optc": "stiff clays", "optd": "gravel", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the frame shown in the below figure, the maximum bending moment in the column is,", "opta": "zero", "optb": "400 kNm", "optc": "100 kNm", "optd": "200 kNm", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a compaction test, as the compaction effort is increased, the optimum moisture content", "opta": "decreases", "optb": "remains same", "optc": "increases", "optd": "increases first and thereafter decreases", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The peak discharge of the instantaneous unit hydrograph of a basin, when compared to the peak discharge of a 4-hour unit hydrograph of that basin, would be", "opta": "greater", "optb": "equal", "optc": "equal or lesser", "optd": "lesser", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The drop manholes are provided in a sewerage system when there is", "opta": "change in alignment of sewer line", "optb": "change in size of sewers", "optc": "change in the elevation of ground level", "optd": "change from gravity system to pressure system", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The reaction time for calculation of stopping distance may be assumed as", "opta": "5 secs", "optb": "2.5 secs", "optc": "0.5 secs", "optd": "10.0 secs", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The percentage error in the computed discharge over a triangular notch corresponding to an error of 1% in the measurement of the head over the notch, would be", "opta": "1.0", "optb": "1.5", "optc": "2.0", "optd": "2.5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The characteristic strength of concrete is defined as that compressive strength below which not more than", "opta": "10% of results fall", "optb": "5% of results fall", "optc": "2% of results fall", "optd": "None of the above.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Un-factored maximum bending moments at a section of a reinforced concrete beam resulting from a frame analysis are 50, 80, 120 and 180 kNm under dead, live, wind and earthquake loads respectively. The design moment (kNm) as per IS: 456-2000 for the limit state of collapse (flexure) is", "opta": "195", "optb": "250", "optc": "345", "optd": "372", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The microbial quality of treated piped water supplies is monitored by", "opta": "Microscopic examination", "optb": "Plate count of heterotrophic bacteria", "optc": "Coliform MPN test", "optd": "Identification of all pathogens", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 5-day BOD of a wastewater sample is obtained as 190 mg/l (with k = 0.01 h-1). The ultimate oxygen demand (mg/l) of the sample will be", "opta": "3800", "optb": "475", "optc": "271", "optd": "190", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A tube well having a capacity of 4 m3/hour operates for 20 hours each day during the irrigation season. How much area can be commanded if the irrigation interval is 20 days and depth of irrigation is 7 cm ?", "opta": "1.71 x 104 m2", "optb": "1.14 x 104 m2", "optc": "22.9 x 104 m2", "optd": "2.29 x 104 m2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}